[
    {
        "question": "Why did Nathaniel Hawthorne add the “w” to his last name?",
        "a": "to dissociate himself from his loyalist ancestors",
        "b": "to separate himself from his tragic childhood",
        "c": "to clarify the pronunciation of his name for readers",
        "d": "to distance his family from the Salem witch trials",
        "e": "to establish a new identity for his writing career",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the death of Nathaniel Hawthorne’s father, the family moved in with the",
        "a": "Bradys",
        "b": "Mannings",
        "c": "Lawrences",
        "d": "Rodgers",
        "e": "Prescotts",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following poets became good friends with Nathaniel Hawthorne in college?",
        "a": "Robert Browning",
        "b": "Emily Dickinson",
        "c": "Henry Wadsworth Longfellow",
        "d": "Ralph Waldo Emerson",
        "e": "Edgar Allen Poe",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1828 Nathaniel Hawthorne published his first novel titled",
        "a": "The Blithedale Romance",
        "b": "The Marble Faun",
        "c": "Fanshawe",
        "d": "Wakefield",
        "e": "Twice Told Tales",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nathaniel Hawthorne became a member and investor in the",
        "a": "Fruitlands Community",
        "b": "Shakers Community",
        "c": "New Harmony Community",
        "d": "Oneida Community",
        "e": "Brook Farm Community",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nathaniel Hawthorne published “Rappacicni’s Daughter” in the",
        "a": "Monthly Anthology",
        "b": "American Magazine of Useful and Entertaining Knowledge",
        "c": "The Atlantic Monthly",
        "d": "Philadelphia Literary Magazine",
        "e": "United States Magazine",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nathaniel Hawthorne wrote The Scarlet Letter in part to",
        "a": "honor his good friend Zachary Taylor",
        "b": "criticize political opponents of Franklin Pierce",
        "c": "provide commentary on the social norms of the period",
        "d": "spread abolitionist ideas leading up to the Civil War",
        "e": "compensate for losing his job",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following authors dedicated a novel to Nathaniel Hawthorne?",
        "a": "Washington Irving",
        "b": "James Fenimore Cooper",
        "c": "Henry David Thoreau",
        "d": "Mark Twain",
        "e": "Herman Melville",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nathaniel Hawthorne lived in all of the following locations EXCEPT",
        "a": "New York City, New York",
        "b": "Raymond, Maine",
        "c": "Concord, Massachusetts",
        "d": "Liverpool, England",
        "e": "Boston, Massachusetts",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The introduction of Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter” claims its original author is M. de",
        "a": "Couronne d'Epines",
        "b": "l’Aubepine",
        "c": "Mûre",
        "d": "Buisson Vif",
        "e": "L’acacia",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” the center of Rappaccini’s garden features a",
        "a": "statue",
        "b": "tree",
        "c": "fountain",
        "d": "greenhouse",
        "e": "pool",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Beatrice refers to the purple plant as her",
        "a": "goddess",
        "b": "friend",
        "c": "child",
        "d": "sister",
        "e": "mother",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Dr.Rappaccini spends his time cultivating",
        "a": "insects",
        "b": "herbs",
        "c": "fruits",
        "d": "vegetables",
        "e": "poisons",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” which of the following animals dies at Beatrice’s feet?",
        "a": "lizard",
        "b": "squirrel",
        "c": "dog",
        "d": "mouse",
        "e": "bird",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Giovanni gives Beatrice a",
        "a": "necklace",
        "b": "watch",
        "c": "bouquet",
        "d": "bracelet",
        "e": "book",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Giovanni sees the plants in Rappaccini’s garden as",
        "a": "withering",
        "b": "unimpressive",
        "c": "small",
        "d": "unnatural",
        "e": "beautiful",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Professor Baglioni tells Giovanni the story of a poisonous girl sent to",
        "a": "Julius Caesar",
        "b": "Genghis Khan",
        "c": "Hannibal",
        "d": "Alexander the Great",
        "e": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following characters gives Giovanni an antidote in Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter?”",
        "a": "Professor Baglioni",
        "b": "Beatrice",
        "c": "Doctor Rappaccini",
        "d": "Benvenuto Cellini",
        "e": "Lisabetta",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following animals does Giovanni kill with his breath in Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter?”",
        "a": "spider",
        "b": "mouse",
        "c": "cat",
        "d": "cricket",
        "e": "ant",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Rappaccini views Beatrice as",
        "a": "brave",
        "b": "capable",
        "c": "powerful",
        "d": "miserable",
        "e": "smart",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Beatrice kills herself with a(n)",
        "a": "rope",
        "b": "antidote",
        "c": "sword",
        "d": "pistol",
        "e": "poison",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "The opening of Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter” claims the story is the English version of",
        "a": "L’Artiste du Beau",
        "b": "La Soiree du Chateau en Espagne",
        "c": "Le Culte de Feu",
        "d": "Contes deux fois racontees",
        "e": "Beatrice; ou la Belle Empoisonneuse",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following novels features an introduction praising an imaginary author?",
        "a": "The House of Seven Gables",
        "b": "The Birthmark",
        "c": "The Scarlet Letter",
        "d": "The Twice-Told Tales",
        "e": "The Marble Faun",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why does Giovanni travel to Padua in Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter?”",
        "a": "He is going on a summer vacation.",
        "b": "His job required him to move there.",
        "c": "He is studying medicine.",
        "d": "He is visiting a family member.",
        "e": "He wanted to meet the great doctor Rappaccini.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following traits BEST foreshadows Rappaccini’s degenerate soul in Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter?”",
        "a": "his balding head",
        "b": "his wrinkled fingers",
        "c": "his shaky voice",
        "d": "his skinny frame",
        "e": "his careful demeanor",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” Nathaniel Hawthorne references",
        "a": "Boccaccio’s The Decameron",
        "b": "Cervantes’ Don Quixote",
        "c": "Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet",
        "d": "Dante’s Divine Comedy",
        "e": "Chaucer’s The Canterbury Tales",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following terms does NOT describe the flowers of the purple plant in Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter?”",
        "a": "beautiful",
        "b": "deadly",
        "c": "foul-smelling",
        "d": "gem-like",
        "e": "serpentine",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first woman achieve the rank and salary of a full professor in the United States?",
        "a": "Cecilia Payne-Gaposchkin",
        "b": "Emily Vermeule",
        "c": "Dorrit Cohn",
        "d": "Helen Maud Cam",
        "e": "Harriette Cooke",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne’s “Rappaccini’s Daughter,” both Giovanni and Beatrice kill a",
        "a": "rabbit",
        "b": "sapling",
        "c": "bird",
        "d": "lizard",
        "e": "bouquet",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following themes does Beatrice BEST emobdy?",
        "a": "Patience leads to triumph.",
        "b": "Love conquers all.",
        "c": "Seeking revenge is futile",
        "d": "True goodness is not corruptible.",
        "e": "Kindness is always rewarded.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    }
]

